

Back End Developer

Phone (520) 709-1298

Email: art_a_henry@yahoo.com

Website: https://arthur-portfolio

Linkedin: linkedin.com/arthur-henry-contact info Address: 43469 West Caven Drive Maricopa, AZ. 85138

Summary

As a software developer my responsibilities vary from day-to-day, allowing for a wide variety of experiences and challenges from project-to-project. I'm able to provide best business practice for design, development and execution of software solutions.

Core Competencies

JavaScript AWS HTML5 CSS3 JAVA Rest API Angular React MongoDB Maven NodeJS MySQL

Professional Experience

ELPHA, San Francisco, CA.

August 2020 – Present

Back End Developer

- Deploy Spring Boot applications using Elastic Beanstalk and AWS CICD tools.
- Work with business analyst to understand the business models and goals.
- Optimized company's compliant handling, reducing boilerplate code and creating highly efficient application.
- Connect Restful Services API for interfacing server side logic with front end user interface using, HTML5,
 CSS3, and modern JavaScript to develop interactive and responsive websites.
- Use React framework to create single page application (SPA) that binds data to specific views and synchronize data.

HEWLETT PACKARD, Phoenix, AZ.

June 2017 – August 2020

Front End Developer

- Develop a customer support platform, using Angular.
- Understanding Angular component logic, and developing a layout of an application.
- Create SPA's for login for main page containing favorites and page for continuous integration configuration.
- Build and execute a brand new customer resolution management tool using Angular and Java to
 efficiently monitor, encode, and resolve customer questions and concerns.
- Work with payment team to save over 50,000 customers time and improve cash flow through development of modern, responsive customer experience.

SPRINT-PARANET, Chicago, IL.

Senior Software Engineer

March 2013 - June 2017

- Work with engineering managers to develop and improve world-class coding standards, design patterns.
- Build applications with reliability and scalability to meet customer demands.
- Develop, document, test, and debug new and existing software systems and applications.
- Modify HTML, JavaScript, and CSS web pages to optimize the page's performance for faster loading and browsing.
- Worked in a team environment to develop and maintain business solutions to increase profits through adopting an Agile approach.

Education

Keller Graduate School of Management Master Degree

Master's in Computer Information Systems June 2016 to August 2018 **DeVry University** Bachelor Degree Bachelor's in Computer Science

Bachelor's in Computer Science
March 2011 to June 2015